<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories.atom"/>
  <title>Cowboy - Stories</title>
  <updated>2021-02-18T16:59:59+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Cowboy</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/joshua-page</id>
    <published>2021-02-18T16:59:59+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-01-24T09:19:10+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/joshua-page"/>
    <title>Joshua Page</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juliet Cass</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>A London Made Closer</h1>
<h2>Joshua Page has lived in London for just over a decade. These days he rides an hour across the capital from his home in Croydon to his work at the National Gallery overlooking Trafalgar Square. He tells of a city put in perspective by cycling, offering a view not obscured in the underground but in full colour and motion at street level. No stranger to starting afresh in a new field, the thread of his various projects is a commitment to craft. The cycling rag he founded <em>The Domestique</em> brings together a like-minded community of “nutters” to inspire Londoners to get on a bike. At a moment in time where virtual takes on a new reality, Josh’s story throws physical things into relief. We cast our minds to things that last – things with touch and tenure – whether they’re crafted from wood or the stories of an impassioned community of riders.</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"That's the good thing about riding in London. It makes the city feel closer."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Tell us about your work.</strong></p>
<p>I'm a framing conservation technician at the National Gallery. I work on antique frames, say they need a repair or resizing to fit a Cézanne or a Van Gogh they would have originally gone with. The gallery makes its money from pictures going in and out on loan and I glaze the artworks and get them safe to travel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_0696_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612880324" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048" style="float: none;"></p>
<p><strong>There must be times you can’t believe you’re up so close. Of the art you’ve handled, which piece impressed you most? </strong></p>
<p>There’s certain works that whenever you get up close, they have an effect on you. A Goya always strikes me, you’re just so aware of what you’re handling. The use of colour, and it's just got a quality – I don't know, it’s hard to explain. These pieces are quite special. There’s an element of knowing your craft – woodwork is an essential skill in what I do.</p>
<p><strong>Of course London is great for exhibitions. Do you go much yourself?</strong></p>
<p>For a while, I didn't go to any at all because it was too much like work. It's kind of come back now. With my National Gallery pass I get entry to the Royal Academy and they always have special exhibitions there. I'm a huge fan of Picasso and we were lucky enough to catch that show last year. That was one of the best I've ever been to. They had not only the finished printworks but the plates and the whole process documented in this exhibition. For someone involved in the mechanics of art, it was nice to see.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_0301_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612880017" alt="electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;"></p><p><strong>It can’t be bad calling The National Gallery your office. </strong></p>
<p>It's cool because I cycle every day up Whitehall [home to UK Government buildings, lined with iconic landmarks]. You can see the National Gallery the whole way up. It’s shown a lot on TV and it’s cool to say I work there. I'm based in a woodwork shop in the dungeons of the gallery. [laughs]. It reminds me of wood-working studios at school where I’d think “I might want to grow up and do this”. That’s kind of come round now and I'm working in this amazing building in a studio that suits me, so it's pretty cool.</p>
<p><strong>Right there in the heart of things, there’s a lot at your fingertips.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. If it's a nice day I'll go for a walk or maybe to a gallery or the many shops round there. It really depends on the weather. In my spare time I make my own furniture and sometimes in my breaks I use the tools from the shop to chip away at something I’m working on.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_1250_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612884588" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Is that a side project of yours? </strong></p>
<p>It's just an interest really. It's taken off in the last year or so as I have the time with lockdown. I wasn't working for a good few months so I cycled a lot and made furniture at home. I make good presents too, it's handy for that. I'm currently making bedside tables and I made some stools for Christmas presents.</p>
<p><strong>My uncle used to start his carpentry at 5am every morning. For my mother's 40th birthday, he made a swinging seat with her date of birth in roman numerals. She’s had it twenty years.</strong></p>
<p>I think that's just so special because you do end up keeping these things your whole life. You know the work and craft that went into it. The carpenter made it exactly how they wanted it to be and these pieces will stay in your life. These things last.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>There’s an element of knowing your craft – woodwork is an essential skill in what I do.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Let’s talk bikes. Have you always cycled to work?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah I cycle to and from work every day and I live in Croydon so that's quite a commute. It's an hour each way and it definitely keeps me fit. I've lived in London 11 years and biking is the best way to get around for me. Even if it's raining outside, I'd much prefer to cycle than be on a bus or feeling claustrophobic on the Tube.</p>
<p><strong>Did you cycle as a kid?</strong></p>
<p>Actually when I was younger, I used to build bikes. Fixies and single-speed bikes as they had in Red Hook Crit, but I didn’t ride much. Then about seven or eight years ago I got into biking and it’s kind of taken over. It’s my weekends and my evenings. </p>
<p><strong>There's this perception that cycling in London could be safer, that the infrastructure hasn’t caught up with other parts of Europe.</strong></p>
<p>I think it's a mixture. There are way more lanes than there used to be. My girlfriend recently started cycling and she was nervous about going on the roads to start. Confidence is a part of it and always being aware. Once you start, it quickly becomes second nature. </p>
<p><strong>Do you use the new lanes put in place for lockdown?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, although I find them quite annoying actually. They feel like an afterthought. By contrast, the Superhighways are really well done. The best bit of Superhighway in London goes the whole way along the embankment. You don't come into contact with cars at all. It's a really lovely ride.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_2572_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612884815" alt=""></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_3216_2048x2048.jpg?v=1612885290" alt="electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048"></div>
<br>
<p><strong>London’s so sprawling, we need these quick routes across. </strong></p>
<p>I think London seems massive too, but when you're on a bike it reduces the size of it. Depending on your pace, you can reach most places in thirty minutes. That's the good thing about riding in London – it makes the city feel closer. You get to places comfortably – especially when you've got a motor behind you.</p>
<p><strong>Yeah, I don’t mind that extra kick. </strong></p>
<p>Definitely. You can feel like you’re chopping and changing with buses and tubes. Whereas if you’re on a bike, that's the one thing you do. From your doorstep all the way to work. I find there’s something cool about riding to go for dinner and then cycling home. There’s something in that self-sufficiency.</p>
<p><strong>How do you know our photographer, Matt Ben Stone?</strong></p>
<p>It’s a nice evolution. I met Matt at a road race in East London six years back. He took some pictures of me just by chance and I used them in the cycling blog I was running. It grew from there. A year or so after, I wanted to make something physical you could have and hold. So we got together and launched a magazine, <a href="https://thedomestiquemag.com/" target="_blank" title="The Domestique" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Domestique</em></a>, centred on the London cycling scene and the community around it. Here he is again, years later, getting shots of me on a Cowboy. </p>
<p><strong>What’s behind the name of the magazine?</strong></p>
<p>Say your team has the yellow jersey in the Tour de France, everyone except the frontrunner would be a <em>domestique</em>. So, if the rider in pole position needs a bottle of water, the <em>domestique</em> gets it and circles back to him. If he needs to be paced up a mountain, they'd be in front shielding him from the wind. The name is inspired by the notion of community. Our idea of <em>The Domestique</em> is to back anyone to get on a bike and ride.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/Dom_group_2_2048x2048.png?v=1613477841" alt=""></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The name is inspired by the notion of community. Our idea of <i>The Domestique</i> is to back anyone to get on a bike and ride.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What's a typical story you might feature?</strong></p>
<p>It’s really for the London community, the average Joe like me who rides to work every day and sometimes a bit further afield on the weekend. We feature anyone who has a story to tell on their bike. Once I spoke to a 70-year-old who was still racing. That's just the coolest grandad you could ever wish for. Any inspirational story like that drew me in.</p>
<p><strong>I'd love to get my hands on a copy.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah I’ll post you one. </p>
<p><strong>Thanks. I know cycling communities can be pretty passionate.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, we’re a load of nutters. [laughs]. Certainly enthusiastic. What was great about that community is that everyone was chipping in. Matt would input his amazing photography and there were a few designers around who would keep the magazine looking good. The whole thing came together through cycling. The community is quite radical in some ways – always pushing limits, always seeing what else can be done.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/MBS_COWBOY_STORIES_LDN-JOSH_PAGE_0879_2048x2048.jpg?v=1613475675" alt="electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;"></p><p><strong>On that theme, when in your life have you felt the most cowboy?</strong></p>
<p>Well, to keep it to bikes – I’d wanted to go backpacking for ages, I’d read so many books on it, and last year I went for the first time in the Peak District. I went on my own with my mountain bike, my tent, and my cooking gear strapped to it and to me. There was something that felt good about just being on my own and doing it. I’d never found the time for it, but this weekend just became available where I could.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The biking community is quite radical in some ways – always pushing limits, always seeing what else can be done.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>And you did it.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. It was cool. I had a plan of sorts, but I kept it loose and changed on how I was feeling.</p>
<p><strong>Any hairy moments?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, plenty. [laughs] I'm new to mountain biking – and it's scary up there. The trails are gnarly and I had a tonne of hair-raising moments involving large boulders and steep cliffs you're tracing up and down. After a while, I had a trick. I let mountain bikers go ahead of me and I watched what they did. Then I'd cheat and follow them down afterwards. [laughs]. I felt every time I did it that I got better and better. By the end, every time I got down the mountain without putting my foot down or falling off, it felt like an achievement.</p>
<p><strong>You're inspiring me to go and do something like this. </strong></p>
<p>Yeah, it's fun. I definitely recommend it, especially having all your life attached to you and your bike. Where you live, where you sleep, where you eat, everything is tied to you. You pull into these remote places, set up camp and make dinner for the night, completely self-sufficient. All you need is your bike.</p>
<p><strong>That's a good Cowboy moment. And I've heard a few. </strong></p>
<p>Okay, good. There's pressure on that. [laughs]</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/charles-johnson</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T23:17:08+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T02:39:33+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/charles-johnson"/>
    <title>Charles Johnson</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Earning Your Stripes. Humanistic Design Takes Pole Position.</h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Designer, maker, and idealist Charles Johnson grew up between U.S. and German cultures, which instilled a sense of openness at an early age. Following 10 years at Puma, the last five as Global Director of Innovation, he’s transitioned his professional life to realize a lasting impact in his career with a focus on sustainability, zero emissions, and equality in the tech startup realm. Charles calls Nuremberg, Germany home, frequently calling upon its heritage of design and mobility to fuel his work and his love for building and racing motorcycles. We meet him at his studio, then take a spin on his Cowboy bike around the track. Along the way, he shares what those who have come before can teach us and how design can change the world. “The answers are there,” he shares. “You just have to want to find them.”</span></h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"I'm an idealist. I believe in the power of design and then I act on it."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What brought you to Nuremberg?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I come from a multicultural family. My mother was German, my father American. I had grown up in America exposed to German culture and had traveled here, so living here was always on my radar. When I was in Colorado working at Crocs as the creative director there, I got a call from a headhunter who talked about an opportunity in Europe for a company involved in motorsports. And I'm very much into motorcycles, so that was a draw.</span></p>
<p><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_08_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610912076" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></strong></p>
<p><strong>And sports in general, right?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah. I've been in the sports industry for quite some time, but the idea of working within motorsports was kind of a dream. And being in a leadership position at Puma in that space was very attractive. So that's what brought me here 10 years ago.</span></p>
<p><strong>Did it live up to your expectations?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Absolutely, yeah. I've been at Puma now for 10 years, or had been. I left there recently. In those 10 years, it drew upon every competency that I'd built up until that point, and then some. And so it was really a sort of intense 10 years. And it got me to a new level in my career.</span></p>
<p><strong>Is there anything about motorsports in particular that really drives you?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I simply dreamed about motorcycles when I was a child. For no good reason. Nobody in my family had motorcycles. I didn't know anybody who did. And so the moment when I had enough expendable income I invested in a motorcycle. And from then on, I just built on it. For me, motorcycling is this holistic experience. I design motorcycles, I build them, and I race them. When you race motorcycles, you can’t think of much else. There are few things in life that require that kind of focus.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_13_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610911797" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_03_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610913756" alt="electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048"></div>
<p><strong>Having been in the design field in the U.S. and in Europe, how do you contrast the two?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Professionally, not so much because I’ve stayed in this industry. And the way you design and develop products is more or less the same. But there is a different culture. In Germany, there’s an emphasis on what they call Ausbildung, which is a proven education and practice that qualifies you for certain roles. In America there is more emphasis on talent and potential than on credentials. There are pros and cons to both "systems".</span></p>
<p><strong>I’ve heard you speak about calling upon past influences in your work. Like the Bauhaus for example. Do you see the design community honoring those influences or do you feel like you’re kind of…</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">...A dinosaur. [laughter]</span></p>
<p><strong>One of the few, huh. What’s your take on where the design world sits now?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The truth is, I may be an outlier in that regard because I do find there is less appreciation for those kinds of things. Anecdotally, I visited the Bauhaus early when I came to Europe and I happened to be talking to one of my designers while I was there, a young designer. I said, “Hey, I’m at the Bauhaus.” And he just didn’t really respond. I’m like, “Do you know what the Bauhaus is?” And he didn’t. That’s sort of the sad truth.</span></p>
<p><strong>Why do you think that is?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I've discovered is that corporate design is not really asking for a certain depth in creativity, especially when you get into industries like consumer industries. Like sports, they're part fashion, part function. They are pulled into this cyclical seasonal newness all the time. Sure, technology and innovation have longer cycles. But the day-in-day-out business is less about depth and more about surface. So designers aren’t digging for those skills. Production is also often far away; little is made locally anymore. So if you’re removed from the actual making you don’t really need that skill. However, I think young designers are good at using digital tools and technologies so there is a healthy exchange.</span></p>
<p><strong>How were you able to achieve depth in your design work at Puma since surely you had to answer to the cyclical nature of the business there too?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of it is a passion and a belief that design can change the world. Holding myself, and then my team, to certain standards. It's about taking the higher road, not the easy road, that’s what I've stood for. My desire and my interest is to make things beautiful and better, not making things that are okay or just fit a brief. And that takes a certain mindset. And then fortunately, being in a leadership position, to be able to establish and nurture that approach.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"Design is a thinking activity, not purely an aesthetic one."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>When did this belief that design can change the world begin to take hold?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Early on the seeds were planted when I was at Carnegie Mellon studying design, where I had some really excellent mentors and teachers. Design was seen as a serious activity, not individual whimsy. You're moving lots of people, for example, in a transit system or you're creating medical equipment. You're shaping that industry in a certain way. And then computer technology came along. And so I was impacted early to understand that design is a thinking activity, not purely an aesthetic one.</span></p>
<p><strong>There is an impact sports can have though, universally across cultures.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes. It's a positive impact pursuit. It can be, very much so. And it's pure. There's a certain science to it. That's what really kept me engaged and bringing in some of those let's say “traditional” product design approaches to sports. When we're talking footwear in particular, it’s a very craft-based industry. Injecting it with design, product design, research, manufacturing to really evolve it is what product designers brought to the industry. And then it's part soft goods, part hard goods, which is an interesting mashup.</span></p>
<p><strong>Just so I’m clear, when you say soft and hard…</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like a shoe has molded parts of plastic and foam, and then soft flexible textiles.</span></p>
<p><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_14_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610912962" alt="footwear design"></strong></p>
<p><strong>Right, okay.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course now, footwear also has digital technologies. That’s a whole other dimension, right?</span></p>
<p><strong>Yes, that’s offering new depth to design for sure.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In your world, Cowboy, that’s more serious in my thinking.</span></p>
<p><strong>Sure. Some days it’s a daily churn. You’ve gotta sell more bikes, you know? But it always comes back to the mission, thinking about the material impact we can have for people in cities.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, that’s another part of my answer to your question. I'm an idealist. I believe in the power of design and then I act on it. I’m the kind of person who has to have that sort of idealism and imagination to shape a vision. I get people into this mindset of, “Hey, we want to go here. Do you see it? It’s not going to be easy and we only have some parts, but let’s go here.” That’s the part that draws me. Then of course we have to deliver to the bottom line, right? So both ideals and results have to come together.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_07_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610914149" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></span></p>
<p><strong>From what I’ve read, your idealism comes a lot from your upbringing. Your parents let you be who you wanted to be. Was that a conscious decision on their part or did it just happen more organically?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That's a very good question. I think my short answer is it was organic. There were certain principles, let's say, that existed. Education was one. Being a good human was another. And being cultured, not in the sense of material ways, but in experiential ways. That was the DNA within the family. Layer on top of that different cultures coming together. For a Black man who grew up in a ghetto in the South Side of Chicago to make his way through college and then the military and to Europe to study for his doctorate where he met a white German woman whose father was a civil servant and whose mother was creative. My mother's very creative, actually. For those two people to come together and then create this family, you have to be quite open. And, the experience of race. Being Black in America for example. And the challenges you're faced with. You've got to work hard.</span></p>
<p><strong>You’ve got to keep fighting.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even as my parents eventually got divorced and my mother found herself a single mother, she was like, “We’re going to get through it. You know we’ll make it. So maybe that’s where it comes from.</span></p>
<p><strong>You recently made the move from Puma to start your own biz. What made you make the shift?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let's say I've left Puma and I'm open to doing different things. It was kind of the culmination of something that started several years ago. I came across something called </span><a href="https://copenhagenletter.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Copenhagen Letter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which was kind of a call to arms for designers to use our powers to make the world a better place. And that was in 2017. And it really spoke to me because I have, again, part of that thinking – I love my career and we're doing fun stuff. I'm creating things that athletes, celebrities, and consumers wear. It's great when you see a famous athlete performing in something you designed or you step out of the subway in New York and see someone wearing your shoes. That's all fun. But on a bad day it feels like I'm not contributing as I could to making the world a better place. So I started to have that longing to do something else. But what I did at Puma, was I started just to shift some of the focus of my professional work. By then I was director of innovation, and so, I started to bring some of that thinking into our agenda. Devoting more to sustainable efforts and more into health and wellness. Some ways that I could make an impact for the brand.</span></p>
<p><strong>Were there key aspects of sustainability that you focused on? It’s such a broad term.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mostly sustainable materials, new ways of using materials and making things. And then more recently, bio design, which uses bacteria to shape the product. We put nature to work for us.</span></p>
<p><strong>Oh, do you know of the Biofabricate Conference?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, and that's where bio design fits in. Puma was on the forefront. Nobody was really doing that. So, that was part of my drive too, to do something that nobody else was doing. I wanted to do something beyond adhering to certain standards, ethical standards, sustainability standards. I'm a product maker, so I think, "How is it that the things we make are different <em>and</em> less harmful to the environment at the same time?" </span></p>
<p><strong>So was there a particular moment that made you take the leap and venture on your own?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I stopped physically going into the office at Puma in February pre-corona so I was already experiencing home office. When corona came in there was something about the solitude, the limitations that caused many people, myself included, to rethink what we're doing and what's really important. And then Black Lives Matter on top of this. It's been a really terrible time for a lot of people, but for me, it's been on some level energizing and creative. So a number of things are coming together to shape where I am right now. The need to get some exercise and this draw to zero emissions and how technology can advance us, that's how I discovered Cowboy. I was not in the market for a bike. I didn't really know much about the e-bike industry let's say. But it caught my eye and attention. And then I sort of followed my nose and discovered the bike.</span></p>
<p><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_02_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610914259" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"Being a designer, I'm drawn to beautiful things. Then you layer in digital technology and immediately, Cowboy rose to the surface."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_01_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610914290" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></strong></p>
<p><strong>What in particular caught your attention?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being a designer, I'm drawn to beautiful things. Then you layer in digital technology, and not just technology for the sake of it but to create a great experience, and immediately, Cowboy rose to the surface. I used to have fun riding a bike as a child. But when I test rode the Cowboy it brought something new to the experience. I thought, "Whoa, cycling is fun again." The Cowboy bike was a rediscovery of how fun cycling can be. And I think, the extra velocity that you can achieve tapped into my motorcycle-ness.</span></p>
<p><strong>I was going to say, that must be part of the draw for you.</strong></p>
<p>No question. I was like, "Of course I'm going to get one." The bike is beautiful hands down. To me, there's no competition. I know there's competition out there, but I don't appreciate it. And then Cowboy really followed through on the experience that a connected product should deliver.</p>
<p><strong>When in your life have you felt the most cowboy?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was another time in my life when I was in New York City. I was hired by Converse as a satellite designer. I took that job and it lasted two years. It ended when they closed the studio in New York, so I converted that into starting my own design consultancy. So that was definitely a moment where I didn't decide, "Hey, I've got to get a job at another sneaker company." Rather I said, "I'm going to start my own shop in New York City." I would say that was a cowboy moment for sure to break out on my own in a city that was highly competitive. I mean, you know New York. If you're not doing it, somebody else is. So you better get on it. That was definitely a cowboy moment.</span></p>
<p><strong>Ah, so then the independent route isn’t your first rodeo.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right, this is the second one.</span></p>
<p><strong>Now that you’re doing your own thing again, is there a certain sphere where you want to have the most impact?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The conversation I'm having out there is about humanistic design and humanistic values so really anything that I do needs to fit into that meaning again of making the world a better place. I like the idea of sustainability but now more focused on zero emissions. And that can be a number of different things. Imagine within the context of a Cowboy or other brands who are focused on getting to zero emissions. I also like shaping product with a sustainable angle to it, either in the product itself or the making of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_11_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610914649" alt="Black Lives Matter"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other aspect is, and this is a pretty involved and deep conversation, but I mentioned the Black Lives Matter Movement surfacing. Being a Black person in this world I have experienced challenges and inequity that has shaped a certain empathy in me. And so, I ask myself, can I do more to counter inequity? Not just racial inequity but also gender inequity. It’s not easy, because there are so many ways to dive in. So I’m trying to understand what I can do in that space, to use my voice and my experience to improve the situation for others.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"The answers are there. You just have to want to find them."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Or even with different organizations, there are so many who need amplification of their work.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So two things. In America for sure, all the answers are there. The research has been done. The case studies have been activated. So I'm engaged in the conversation but sometimes I find myself saying, "You don't need me. The answers are there. You have to want to find them.” That's part one. So then if that's true, what impact can I have that's new and different? And I think there can be, there ought to be, there needs to be, more investment and I actually mean literal investment. So for example, I'm in the tech industry and startup world and the climate is very white.</span></p>
<p><strong>True.</strong></p>
<p>So, that doesn't mean that technology and startups and entrepreneurs can't be Black. It just means maybe they don't have the same tailwinds behind them. Right? And so what can I do to counter that? I have conversations with investors, with incubators and accelerators, and so on. That's an impact I can imagine having. Can I have an impact that's like, “Look guys, what is the climate? What are you investing in?” I can't quote the data, but the idea for example is a company that has more women at the board level do better. So if that's true, we then investing in more of that kind of leadership is good business.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_CharlesJohnson_Brix_Maas_12_2048x2048.jpg?v=1610914727" alt="electric bike for urban riders"></p>
<p><strong>That’s definitely a focus at Cowboy, too.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Europe has an opportunity to get ahead of the curve and to learn lessons, shameful lessons from the U.S. Just by nature of having had that experience America but being here in Europe, I can impart that wisdom, or that experience, to help.</span></p>
<p><strong>Like you said, the answers are there.</strong></p>
<p>Say what you’re going to do, give yourself some metrics, and then do it. You have to challenge yourself as to why are you saying something and do you believe in it? And then, what are you really going to do? That’s the harder part.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/marc-schmitz</id>
    <published>2020-11-23T09:13:04+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-17T21:24:29+01:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/marc-schmitz"/>
    <title>Marc Schmitz</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>Between East and West, a State of Openness</h1>
<h2>While renowned artist and curator Marc Schmitz hails from Germany, his embracing of the philosophies of the Far East made his art flourish. He was most drawn to the open expanses and nomadic culture of Mongolia where he is the founder and artistic director of Biennial Land Art Mongolia, now celebrating its 10th year. We talk with Marc in his studio in Kreuzberg Berlin about his latest series, <i>The Nomads Square</i>, and what it means to approach art, and life, with an open mind; creating without brooding but always looking to the future.</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>"It's both a physical and mental experience that is important for me and my art."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What first brought you to Berlin?</strong></p>
<p>This was a long time ago, I think ‘87. Before the wall came down I moved to Berlin. I was lucky because I found a huge studio at that time and started painting and doing artwork.</p>
<p><strong>To be in Berlin right before and after the wall came down must have been an incredible time, on the edge of something new.</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. Before the wall came down we were thinking we were such avant-garde. It was a very special time. We had ideas we were already in the future but living on Mars or something strange. My studio was just around there. You could walk through a tent and you were all of a sudden in a strange jungle, you know? And then it was the end of punk. But Berlin is always in progress. I don’t live in the past. We can never fight against time, it’s impossible.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_09_1024x1024.jpg?v=1605749852" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"I don't live in the past.<br></strong><strong>We can never fight against time; it's impossible."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Word in Berlin today is you have a show going on. Tell us about it.</strong></p>
<p>It’s a two-person show with a colleague of mine [Han Feng]. It’s in a large space nearby. We each have about three different rooms. We did some new work for this. I created two neons. And a selection of my paintings.</p>
<p><strong>Is any of the work in collaboration with each other?</strong></p>
<p>No, not yet. We share another exhibit which is currently in Shanghai. And soon another opening in Bangkok.</p>
<p><strong>How do you know each other?</strong></p>
<p>Han and I were introduced by a curator I know in London. Han had just emigrated to Germany and was looking for a studio. By chance I was able to help him find one and we became friends.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_06_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606073312" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_05_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606073365" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"></p>
<p><strong>Let’s talk about your latest series, The Nomads Square as I think it’s fascinating how creativity has come out of this time period and quarantine. How did it come about?</strong></p>
<p>I started in January. I had a show opening in China but that was the moment I realized something was going to happen. I didn't travel and then there was the lockdown until June. I was just working trying to keep my mind calm. Just drawing. I didn't use any kind of brush at first. For me, it was a good experience because I spent more time in the studio since a decade instead of traveling which takes a lot of time preparing exhibitions. So I’ve been using the studio for what it was meant for, actually. Just doing something every day like a diary and to feel openness. It's conceptual work, but it's to leave the concept. Then I decided to make a documentary book about it to have a better understanding for myself. Before I was doing much larger works but this is a small size.</p>
<p><strong>So you gave yourself a restriction to be within this frame, if you will.</strong></p>
<p>The restriction was not judgment. I don’t judge, I just do them. Then the next one, just one after the other.</p>
<p><strong>When do you come back to it, to look at the body of work?</strong></p>
<p>One of my most important curators told me, do work and then forget about it. In Asian understanding I would say Taoist work. Just be in the environment. Be like water. Do something, next. Too much thinking or critique makes us heavy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>"Do work and then forget about it. Too much thinking or critique makes us heavy."</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_01_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606073626" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"></strong><strong></strong></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_03_47d971bd-0e24-404c-b5f2-d28a6296e7aa_2048x2048.jpg?v=1606159815" alt="art in process" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<p><strong>Tell me more about this approach to your work.</strong></p>
<p>Good artwork is always also entertaining, but it’s a carrier for the content. This is a very basic idea when you create something. In the end, you just have the work. If it needs a lot of explanation, people get a headache.</p>
<p><strong>We just need to absorb it, right?</strong></p>
<p>It begs the decision to not judge. Judgment has to be personal in the end. It can give a good feeling or open the mind or relax it or whatever. But as soon as the work is finished, I can’t control it because it has its own life now in the public.</p>
<p><strong>Being in the studio and not over thinking, was that always something you ascribed to?</strong></p>
<p>For me, it’s very important to feel the entire environment. The studio is like a kind of lockdown with yourself. The park is nearby. I go almost every day with my bike and it’s all these small, uncalculated things that you see. Like in the age when important thinkers like Nietzsche were walking, but biking has a new quality of being open to the environment.</p>
<p><strong>So you see the bike as representing your approach to art?</strong></p>
<p>To bike is a statement. For an individual being in the open environment, it’s different from a car. It’s also an ecological statement. At the moment in Berlin, they are changing a lot of traffic and the streets to set up bikeways. In Mongolia, young people demonstrated to have bikeways. They had no lobby but they were successful. The statement is enough because in these changing times, it’s very important.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"To bike is a statement."</p>
</blockquote>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_08_697f3381-f90b-49fe-b4c6-b8c45db1b71b_2048x2048.jpg?v=1606159952" alt="the electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048"></div>
<p><strong>Do you see more people in Berlin making such a statement?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah. I had an appointment yesterday at the bike shop. It’s almost impossible to get an appointment now because there’s such huge demand.</p>
<p><strong>How did you first come across Cowboy?</strong></p>
<p>I saw an announcement somewhere and I liked that it doesn’t look like any bike. I live on the top of this hill near Viktoriapark and I thought it would make a difference because it’s annoying going up the hill every day. I had a sale of a work and I said yeah okay [laughter].</p>
<p><strong>Ah, put the proceeds to a new Cowboy bike.</strong></p>
<p>Yeah, that's a good option.</p>
<p><strong>During this time, how has Cowboy played a role?</strong></p>
<p>I feel supported. I feel lucky to have this bike. It feels strong, and in these times where you look for only basic things and you need to travel from A to B it’s really useful.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_13_8b0be98b-8adb-40b6-9e87-7b68a8c2a58b_2048x2048.jpg?v=1606160221" alt="the electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048"></div>
<p><strong>Nice one. Okay, switching gears. When in your life did you do something courageous? A real cowboy move?</strong></p>
<p>The big move was inaugurating the Biennial in Mongolia. Most of the work is in very remote places and it's a great experience for me. It's amazing because we have partners around the world participating. So yeah, this was a big move.</p>
<p><strong>When did it begin?</strong></p>
<p>In 2010.</p>
<p><strong>What brought you to do it?</strong></p>
<p>Space. It offered me space. This was for me the most important realization. Personally getting my mind open because we are in boxes and boxes. It’s both a physical and mental experience that is important for me and my art. And this experience I could have in Mongolia much better than for example, in China or Japan or Korea or even here. We own three gers [yurts] in a place about five hours from Ulaanbaatar, near the birthplace of Genghis Khan. I can open the door of my Mongolian home, and I can see for 50 kilometers. It’s just green. I usually go there for two or three months, traveling around. It’s a personal thing that I really enjoy open space.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_07_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606073801" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"></p>
<p><strong>Certainly a different vantage point atop that hill compared to Viktoriapark in Berlin. Where do you find open space here where landscape is mostly developed?</strong></p>
<p>The Park at Gleisdreieck nearby here offers a new movement through the center city. I’m a nomad who's not so good at staying in one place. So I need to move. One statement I’d make is that the future comes in the park.</p>
<p><strong>How so?</strong></p>
<p>Because the park is a place free from anything commercial. It’s different from the street. We need this kind of free space. The park is developed as an artistic environment with the intention of being open.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_11_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606074162" alt="the electric bike for urban riders"> </p>
<p><strong>If you had to sum up this state of openness you talk about, how would you?</strong></p>
<p>Life is circular; step out of the line and enter the field.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/COWBOY_MarcSchmitz_Brix_Maas_04_1024x1024.jpg?v=1606074234" alt="Marc Schmitz"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/john-prigogine</id>
    <published>2020-09-30T18:27:56+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T18:27:56+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/john-prigogine"/>
    <title>John Prigogine</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h1>A Case for Reinvention</h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">It takes guts to leave the career you know to open a restaurant, and true dedication to survive let alone make it a rousing success. That’s precisely what John Prigogine did in opening <a href="https://oldboyrestaurant.be/" target="_blank" title="OLD BOY Restaurant" rel="noopener noreferrer">OLD BOY</a> in Brussels with his business partner Xavier Chen. While their journey hasn’t been quite as dramatic as its South Korean action thriller namesake, it’s certainly had its twists and turns. When the pandemic hit, it took an even greater resolve than what they had to muster in the early survival days. Luckily, John knows what it takes to reinvent. We spoke with him at the one-year mark of his restaurant opening, then again this summer to hear what it took to give his restaurant concept another look to make sure the Bruxellois could come back for another taste.</span></h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“In Brussels, there are a lot of things that can still be done here.”</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>When COVID-19 hit and you had to close, was it a sure thing you'd be back or was it ever in question?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So this is what happened. The rumor had been confirmed. All restaurants would have to close for an undefined time. We pretty much knew this would happen and we were ready for it. We cleaned up everything, emptied our fridges and dispatched all the food we had. We said goodbye and went home. At this point we didn’t know when we could reopen, and the social distancing rules applying to restaurants in Belgium were not very encouraging. Specifically in our case: a small, 29-seat restaurant, with 15 seats at the counter and 7 tables of 2. If we were to keep a distance of 1.5m between each table, we’d be left with roughly 3 tables of 2 and 6 seats at the counter – so 12 seats total. The math was simple. Considering our functioning costs and our average ticket, it wasn’t looking good. So yes, in the beginning we thought we’d never be able to open again. We hoped to reopen, but it required a little thinking and changing the way we had been doing business for a year and a half.</span> <span style="color: #000000;"><strong></strong></span></p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/Oldboy-221_1024x1024.jpg?v=1601239965" alt="the electric bike for urban riders" style="float: none;" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024"></div>
<p><strong>How did you spend most of your time while you were closed?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the lockdown was announced, we closed both our businesses: OLD BOY the restaurant and LIL BOY the takeaway. LIL BOY could have stayed open, but we decided to close down for a while, doing the right thing at that time. So here I was, forced unemployment, stuck at home. Xavier my partner was covering all the paperwork that followed the closure and I basically had nothing to do. Day to day I’m more the field guy, being around OLD BOY, working closely with the kitchen, the front of house staff, communications…so with the restaurant closed I had a lot of time for myself (I have no kids) and I have to say I did enjoy it a lot. I did relax, play video games, cook a lot, continue to work on new projects, and of course thought of how to keep OB alive (at least on social media) and how we could possibly get OB back on track.</span></p>
<p><strong>What did it take to get OLD BOY back?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After about a month, Xavier and I decided it was time to get LIL B back open. Takeaway was of course booming, and we wanted to be back. The question was to find a way to get OB back on track too. LIL B is OB’s takeaway so we didn’t want OB to do something that LIL B was already doing well. So we came up with a different concept for OB until we could reopen OB this past June: OLD BOY AT HOME. Every week we designed a menu including a marinated meat or fish with two choices of vegetables on the side. The vegetables were pre-cooked and just needed to be reheated at home following our instructions. The meats were marinated and sold raw, also with instructions on how to cook them properly at home. On the side we also sold packs of natural wines, and we continued with our playlists so people could really get that OB feeling at home—cooking and dressing up their food while drinking our wine and listening to our sounds. This was a great success. We were busy every week. We even launched BAOS and WONTONS DIY kits that people could buy on top of our menus. We were selling like crazy.</span></p>
<p><strong>Looking back at when you first opened, what gave you the impetus to start OLD BOY?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I love to cook, I love to eat. I was always trying to understand and think about why this place or that restaurant was working well and what was missing in Brussels. So I had it in mind for a long time. I studied business in Brussels at the Solvay Business School, but I always had this thing about food. I had wanted to go to Lausanne, a famous school if you want to work in hospitality, but my parents weren’t really into it. They thought restaurant life was too hard. When I was working for Sony, I felt like I was one of those guys working in a big company and not meaning a lot, even though I was moving up the ladder. I felt a bit bored because even if I was working for a good company, it was always the same job movie after movie. The only thing that kept me motivated was working on a restaurant concept. Eventually, it became real because we actually found a place for the restaurant. So I had to decide if I was going to quit and try to launch this restaurant or stay in Sony forever. So I quit and opened OLD BOY.</span> </p>
<p><strong>Tell me about the concept. What did you feel Brussels was missing?</strong></p>
<p>In Brussels, there are a lot of things that can still be done. There’s competition of course, but I’ve always felt we were really behind in terms of concept. Xavier is half Taiwanese, I’m half Thai. We’ve traveled to Asia a lot. We’ve also been to London and the U.S. and we saw the kind of places that existed there in terms of Asian restaurants. What you have here are very traditional Asian restaurants—the style of food, the vibe, silly music or no music at all. The old school Asian restaurant. We wanted a restaurant where you would eat good Asian food and the vibe would be nice. We always had in mind those guys from Momofuku in New York, and how there was no place like that here.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/Oldboy-413_1024x1024.jpg?v=1601240940" alt="cowboy e-bike" style="float: none;" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024"></div>
<p><strong>What’s the experience like?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At OB, we only have a menu of roughly 10 dishes. Of the 10 dishes there are three signature ones that are always on the menu. The rest of the dishes change with the season, what we want to cook, and what vegetables are available. So there’s a seasonal component to our menu that was very new for any Asian restaurant in Brussels. Also the idea of sharing food. At OB, sharing is essential because we send every dish one at a time, one after the other. And this was completely new.</span></p>
<p><strong>New for Brussels?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Definitely in terms of an Asian restaurant. There were already a couple of sharing-style restaurants here, but more French or Scandinavian. It’s been a trend for a while, it’s happening everywhere else. But for us, it’s really a souvenir of how we eat when we’re in Asia. Everyone shares everything at the table. It’s essential to the experience.</span></p>
<p><strong>With this new life venture, how has Cowboy fit into it?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we opened the restaurant, we decided why not buy a Cowboy because we really liked the brand. We thought it looked super cool. Of course it’s all black and stylish. It’s modern. I live with the bike 10 minutes from the restaurant and it’s so convenient. I actually lock it at the entrance. A lot of clients come to the restaurant and they see the bike and ask me about it. I’m not going to say I did my research comparing every electric bike. I just wanted an electric bike and I thought the Cowboy was cool and that’s why I bought one.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/Oldboy-261_2048x2048.jpg?v=1601241712" alt="connected electric bike" style="float: none;" width="2048x2048" height="2048x2048"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<p><strong>What do you like most about the bike?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was pretty amazed about the electric assistance of the bike. But what I like about it is it’s a bit sporty. It’s an electric bike that still requires you to cycle.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span><strong>"It's an electric bike that still requires you to cycle. The bike helps me go further."</strong></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>When in your life have you felt the most like a cowboy?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I decided to quit my job at Sony and invest nearly all of my earnings into the restaurant. I didn't have a business plan and I'd never before worked in the food industry. I was comfortable, earning a good life, working 9 to 5...but we had just found a location for the restaurant and had to decide if we signed the lease it meant quitting my job and going all in because it was going to get real, real fast. Opening the restaurant was definitely a cowboy decision in my life, and it's the best decision I've ever made. It was a bet, but it was something I always wanted to try. It meant I would become independent, be my own boss, and start working in an environment that I love.</span></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1772/1703/files/Oldboy-75_1024x1024.jpg?v=1601246535" alt="cowboy e-bike" style="float: none;"></div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><span>"Opening the restaurant was definitely a cowboy decision. It was a bet. It was something I always wanted to try."</span> </strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Were there any moments after you opened the restaurant that gave you second thoughts?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was very tough in the beginning. Xavier and myself were working at the restaurant, arriving at eight in the morning. We were doing the cleaning. Then we were both working as servers. We were our own servers because we wanted to play it safe on our costs and we knew our concept. At noon the service opened, taking orders, serving dishes to the customer, cleaning the tables, dressing the tables again. So usually we finished cleaning everything from the first service half past 4 or 5. Then we had to be ready to open again at 7 in the evening. It was so intense. We were only just waking up to go to the restaurant after sleeping a few hours and then doing everything ourselves.</span> </p>
<p><strong>A labor of love. I’m sure your customers have appreciated your dedication though? That it’s your restaurant and it’s personal.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exactly. I think the fact that we were so involved, that’s what people like too. Even now, we have a great team. The restaurant can function without us. Even so though, I’m always there checking that everything is going well. It’s necessary in this line of business, I think.</span></p>
<p><strong>I think you’d do well in New York. Give those Momofuku guys some competition.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">[laughter] I can’t imagine how someone has the balles to open in New York. I think of the rent and the competition. If it works it’s great, but it could be so tough.</span></p>
<p><strong>It is indeed. Whenever I end up back in Brussels, I’ll come by for a meal.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perfect. I hope to see you one day at the restaurant.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/loic-ganza</id>
    <published>2019-10-22T10:23:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-28T21:36:57+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/loic-ganza"/>
    <title>Loïc Ganza</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/benoit-do-quang</id>
    <published>2019-09-10T11:13:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-28T21:44:06+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/benoit-do-quang"/>
    <title>Benoit Do Quang</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/marco-breier</id>
    <published>2019-09-03T12:29:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:11:43+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/marco-breier"/>
    <title>Marco Breier</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/nicolas-debray</id>
    <published>2019-08-27T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:11:35+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/nicolas-debray"/>
    <title>Nicolas Debray</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/fabian-jean-villanueva</id>
    <published>2019-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:11:52+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/fabian-jean-villanueva"/>
    <title>Fabian Jean Villanueva</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/olivia-borlee</id>
    <published>2019-07-29T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-28T21:46:55+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/olivia-borlee"/>
    <title>Olivia Borlée</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/julie-saverys</id>
    <published>2019-04-17T11:39:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:12:02+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/julie-saverys"/>
    <title>Julie Saverys</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/alexis-houssou</id>
    <published>2019-03-29T10:02:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:12:06+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/alexis-houssou"/>
    <title>Alexis Houssou</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/tom-boon</id>
    <published>2019-03-21T09:11:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:12:19+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/tom-boon"/>
    <title>Tom Boon</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/julie-mazy</id>
    <published>2019-03-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2020-07-31T10:12:12+02:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://cowboy.com/blogs/stories/julie-mazy"/>
    <title>Julie Mazy</title>
    <author>
      <name>Cort Cunningham</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
